拜托啊
Oh,come on!
这也是你们的感恩节
Hey, it's your Thanksgiving too.
除了看足球  你们还可以帮忙
You know, instead of watching football, you could help.
我们知道
We know.
瑞秋  你要将棉花糖排成同心圆
Rachel, you wanna put the marshmallows in concentric circles.
不  是你要把它们排成同心圆
No, you want to put them in concentric circles.
我要这么做
I want to do this.
每年都是这样
Every year.
《老友记》 第三季 第9集  美式足球比赛
Friends S03E09 The One with the Football
（主演：詹妮弗·安妮斯顿）
（主演：柯特妮·考克斯）
（主演：丽莎·库卓）
（主演：马特·勒布朗）
（主演：马修·派瑞）
（主演：大卫·修蒙）
十码  五码  触地得分  巨人队达阵得分
To the 10, to the 5. Touchdown, Giants!
我真的想要看一下比赛
You know, for once, I am gonna try to watch one of these things.
中场休息
Halftime.
谁要玩一下球
Who wants to, uh, throw the ball around?
三对三   那应该会很好玩
Get a little 3-on-3 going? Oh, that would be so much fun!
我能玩吗  我从未玩过足球
Can I play too?I've never played football, ever.
太棒了  你可以防守钱德
Great! You can cover Chandler.
我不想玩
I don't... I don't really want to play.
你跟珍妮丝分手后什么事都没做
You never do anything since you and Janice broke up.
才不是这样
Not true.
我想整天穿着睡袍啃花生
I wanted to wear my bathrobe and eat peanut clusters all day.
一早开始喝酒  别说我没有目标
And start drinking in the morning. Don't say I don't have goals!
你得开始忘了她  好吗
You have to start getting over her, all right?
玩球或许能让你忘记珍妮丝
If you play, maybe it'll take your mind off Janice.
如果你不玩  大家会生你的气  因为两队人数不一样
If you don't, everyone will be mad at you because the teams won't be even.
好吧  我玩就是了
All right, I'll play.
来玩吧  罗斯
Yay! Yay! Let's do it! Ross?
什么  要玩足球吗
What? Wanna play football?
嗯...
Um...
摩妮卡跟我不能玩足球
Monica and I aren't supposed to play football.
谁说的   你们妈妈说的
Says who? Your mom? Ha-ha-ha.
对 对
Yes.
以前每年感恩节我们都会玩足球赛
Ahem. Every Thanksgiving, um, we used to have a touch football game...
它就叫做盖勒杯
...called The Geller Bowl.
不  你得骄傲地说出来才行
No, no, no. You say that proudly!
总之我跟罗斯总是当队长
Anyway, Ross and I were always captains, and, um...
竞争很激烈  有一年  第六届盖勒杯
It got kind of competitive. And one year, Geller Bowl VI...
我不小心打断罗斯的鼻子
...I accidentally broke Ross' nose.
你是故意的
It was so not an accident.
她看到我就快抱住她  就用她的…
She saw I was about to tag her, so she threw...
用她那老奶奶般的粗手臂打我的脸
...her big fat grandma-arm elbow in my face...
然后拼命往前跑
...and just kept running.
对了  我达阵得分获得胜利
To score the winning touchdown, by the way.
哇啊  哦  啊  哦
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Heh.
你没赢  达阵得分不算
Uh, you did not win the game. The touchdown didn't count...
因为你犯规了  非常野蛮地打断了我的鼻子
...because of the spectacularly illegal, and savage, nose-breaking.
我赢了那场比赛
I won the game.
是吗   为什么你没拿到盖勒杯
Yeah? Then how come you didn't get the Geller Cup?
还有盖勒杯
Ahem, there was a Geller Cup?
对  赢的人可以拿到奖杯
Yes, the trophy you got if you won the game.
但爸说没有人赢   他讨厌我们打架
But Dad said nobody won, and he was sick of our fighting.
所以他把奖杯拿走
So he took the trophy...
丢进湖里
...threw it in the lake.
诅咒破解了吗
And was the curse lifted?
总之…
Anyway...
妈说我们再也不准玩足球
...Mom said we weren't allowed to play football again.
你知道吗   我想我们能打一场比赛
You know what? I think we should play a game.
少来了  那是十二年前的事
I mean, come on. It's been 12 years.
我们能谈一谈吗
Can I see you for a second?
胆小鬼
Wuss!
好吧  我们要玩
All right, we're gonna play.
等一下  我们怎么去球场   我妈不让我过街
Wait. How we gonna get there? My mom won't let me cross the street.
来吧
Here you go.
好吧
All right.
开始了  等一下
Let's bring it in. Wait.
甜心  传给我
Honey, throw it to me!
接住了
Here you go. Aah!
你差点打中我的脸
That almost hit me in the face!
我们得选出队长
We have to pick captains.
然后挑选队员
And then "Tennilles."
该怎么选呢
So how do we decide that?
我们何不跳兔子舞  什么
Why don't we just bunny up? What?
兔子  兔子
Bunny!  Bunny!
看起来罗斯跟我是队长
Looks like Ross and I are captains.
好吧  我先跳的  我能先选  乔伊
Okay, so, um, I bunnied first, so I get to pick first. Joey.
谢谢  摩妮卡
Thank you.  Monica.
我是你的好朋友
I'm your best friend.
甜心  别担心  你会被选中的
Sweetie, don't worry, you'll get picked.
钱德
Chandler.
罗斯  菲比
Ross?  Phoebe.
甜心  我挑你了
Sweetie, now I pick you.
你才没有挑我  你是没有选择了
You don't pick me. You're stuck with me!
好吧  就这么办了
Okay. All right. So let's see.
比赛场地从垃圾桶到灯柱  好吗
Let's play from the, uh, trash can to the light post, right?
双手达阵得分  比赛开始了
Two-hand touch. We'll kick off.
各位  听着  我还有28分钟
People, listen. I've got 28 minutes...
然后我得去帮火鸡涂酱汁
...before I have to baste again.
就像在参加职业比赛
Wow, just like in the pros.
好吧  临场会议
Okay, huddle up! Whoo! Woo-hoo.
到这边开临场会议  等等我
Huddle up over here! Wait for me! Wait for me!
酷啊  我的第一次临场会
Oh, cool! My first huddle.
好吧   好吧
Okay. Ha, ha. Okay.
你们对钱德有什么想法
So what do you guys really think of Chandler?
你知道你要做什么吧    对
You know what you're doing, right?  Yeah.
好吧  乔伊接球  我们阻挡
Okay. Joey will catch it. We'll block.
什么是阻挡
What's "block"?
我以为你知道你要做什么   我以为你是指在生活中
I thought you knew what you were doing. I thought you meant in life!
分开
Break!
球是珍妮丝
The ball is Janice. The ball is Janice.
大混蛋
Ow! Son of a...! Ow!
拜托哦   对不起
Come on! I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
你们知道吗   我们要直接丢球
You know what? We're just gonna throw it.
我来接
I got it!
来吧
Go, go, go!
得分  七比零
Score! Seven to nothing!
甜心  你没事吧
Honey, you okay?
来吧  我们走
Come on, let's go.
输家滚开
Whoo. Losers walk.
是吗   输家只爱放话
Yeah? Losers talk.
不  你得跟"输家"押韵
No, no, actually, losers rhyme.
Forty-three...
...74...
你要直接来   对
You wanna go shotgun? Yeah.
开球
Hike.
这边  这里…
One Mississippi... Over here! Over here! Unh.
我差点接到那一球
Ha! I almost caught that one!
太棒了  现在比数是七比差点七
Great. Now the score's seven to almost seven.
好吧  这一球我要你直冲切右
Okay, on this play, I want you to do a down-and-out to the right, okay?
分开  等一下  我要做什么
Break! Wait. What am I gonna do?
你呢
You?
你直接冲
You go long.
冲到哪里
How long?
到你几乎看不见我们为止
Until we start to look very small.
好的  分开  分开
Okay. Break! Break!
预备  开始
Set, hike! One Mississippi...
换边  换边
Switch! Switch! Switch!
不  不
No, no, no, no!
谢谢你帮我们捡球
Hey. Thanks for stopping our ball.
你们在玩美式足球
You are playing American football?
对
Yeah.
你好像是外国人
Wow, you're, like, from a whole other country!
我是荷兰人   我是乔伊
I'm Dutch.Hi, I'm Joey.
我是玛哈
I am Margha.
抱歉  荷兰人  尾音我没听清楚
Sorry, Dutch, I didn't get that last little bit. Ha-ha-ha.
你要玩足球或…我是钱德
You wanna play football or...? Hi, I'm Chandler.
你好  钱德
Hello, Chandler.
她叫荷兰人跟玛汉
Her name is Dutch and also "Margham."
玛哈   玛荷
Margha. Margha.
玛哈
Margha.
玛汉
Mahan.
来吧  大伙们  开始了  第二次十码进攻
Come on, guys! Let's go! Second down!
应该是第三次十码进攻了  才不是  是第二次
Uh, hello? It's third down.  No, it's not. It's second.
怎么了
Wow. "Wow" what?
我很讶异你还是会这么做
It just amazes me that you're still pulling stuff like this. Heh.
什么  本来就是第二次进攻  好吧  第二次
Pulling what? It's second down. Okay, it's second down.
你说是就是
Take all the second downs you need.
我听到了  我本来就说得很大声
I heard that. Well, I said it loud.
我可以在旁边看吗
It is okay if I stay and watch?
就坐那边吧   对  你何不留下来呢
Just sit right there. Yeah, why don't you stick around?
一切进行得很顺利   我也那么想
That went well. I think so.
我想跟她要电话号码
I was thinking about, uh, asking her for her number.
谢了  兄弟  我自己问的话会比较有诚意
Thanks, man, but it makes a stronger statement if I ask for it myself.
我是想自己追她  为了忘记珍妮丝
I was thinking about for me, as part of that getting-over-Janice thing.
对  没错
Oh, yeah. That.
如果这么重要  我就让你追她
If it means that much, I'll let you have her.
谢谢
Thanks.
什么   让我追她
Wh...? "Let me have her"?
你是说你不让我的话  我就毫无机会吗
You mean if you didn't, I wouldn't have a shot?
我真的不想说出来
I don't like to say it out loud...
但事实就是如此
...but yeah!
每个人都有自己的优点  你对数字就比较在行
We all have our strengths. You're better with numbers and stuff.
数学   你要跟我提数学的事
Math? You're giving me math?
好吧  你知道吗  算了
All right, you know what? Forget about it.
你也能追那个女孩  看谁能追到
You go for the girl. We'll see who gets her.
钱德  我要你跑向球门左边  甜心
I want you to run a post-pattern to the left. And, sweetie...
对  我知道  继续跑
Yeah, I know. Go long.
我只是在人群中前后跑动
All I'm doing is running back and forth from the huddle.
你想待在那边吗
Well, uh, you wanna just stay out there?
球能给我一下吗   好的
Can I see that for a second? Yeah.
好的  好的  开始了
Okay. Okay, let's go.
我来盯钱德  开始
I got Chandler   Hike!
一  二  三
One Mississippi, two Mississippi, three Mississippi.
掉球
Fumble!
你有什么毛病   这是我最喜欢的球衣
What's the matter with you? This is my favorite jersey.
现在你有两件了
Well, now you have two.
我对数学真的很在行
Hey, I am good at math!
够了  我还是要让你去追她
That's it. I was still gonna let you have her.
现在准备好好难过一场吧
But now, prepare to feel bad about yourself.
我一辈子都在为那个做准备
I've been preparing for that my entire life!
或是为了你的不礼貌
Or something about you that's mean!
来吧  各位  开始了
Come on, guys. Let's go.
追平比数  没时间了
Tie score. We're running out of time.
42 , 38   开始
Forty-two, 38, hike!
我来接
I got it! Ooh! Ugh!
我的咪咪受伤了
Broken boobs! Ow.
菲比   快跑  跑  菲比
Pheebs, run! Run, Phoebe! Run!
天啊  没错  达阵得分  达阵得分
God! Touchdown! Touchdown! Yes! Touchdown! Hey, oh!
不
No, no, no.
闹钟响了  那一球不算
Uh, the buzzer buzzed. It doesn't count.
在接到球之后  在接到球之前
After the snap.   Before the snap.
之后  之前
After. Before.
那很重要吗   对
Does it really matter? Yes!
但我达阵得分  那是我第一次达阵得分
But I made a touchdown. It was my first touchdown.
菲比  那真的很棒  可惜不算
Pheebs, that's great. Doesn't count.
那一球算数  作弊鬼  霸道女王
Does so count. Cheater, cheater, compulsive eater.
天啊
Oh, my God!
没关系  或许你没长大  但我已经长大了
That's fine. Maybe you haven't grown up, but I have.
好吧  去死吧
Oh, okay. Dead leg!
好吧  你想靠作弊赢球  尽管去吧
Okay, fine. You want to win by cheating, go ahead.
达阵得分算数  你们赢了
The touchdown does count. You win.
不
Whoo! Yay! - No!
我不要再这么做  我要你输得无话可说
I won't do this again. I wanna beat you when you can't blame it...
鼻子断了  铃声响了  或你可能白血球过多
...on the broken nose or the buzzer or the fact that you might have mono.
就说双方平手  现在是中场休息
Let's just call this tie score and it's halftime.
首先我不跟作弊的人比赛
First, I don't play with cheaters.
其次你知道我的扁桃腺肿了起来
Second of all, you know I had swollen glands!
你知道吗   我想你会玩的
You know what? I think you'll play.
真的吗   为什么
Oh, really? Why's that?
因为赢的人可以拿到这个
Because the winner gets this.
盖勒杯
The Geller Cup!
大家都看到  那个钉在木板上的丑娃娃了吗
Is everybody else seeing a troll doll nailed to a two-by-four?
啊哦
Mm-hm.
好吧  太好了
Okay, good.
好了  它怎么会在你手上
Okay, where the hell did you get that?
你到医院去接鼻梁的时候…
When you went to the hospital for your nose...
我游到湖里把它捞出来的
...I swam into the lake and fished it out.
奖杯是我的
That cup is mine!
不  才不是  想要把它带回家  你就得赢球
No, it's not. You want it, you're gonna have to win it.
我们不吃晚餐了吗
So are we not having dinner at all?
来吧  开始了  认真点  小组会议
Come on, let's go. It's time to get serious. Huddle up.
专心在比赛上
Keep your head in the game.
真的很难  他在那个荷兰女孩旁边开小组会议
It's hard, you know? His huddle's close to the Dutch girl.
如果我在带球时扑倒钱德  你能专心一点吗
If I take Chandler out of the running, will you be able to focus?
你打算怎么做   确定让他接到球
What are you gonna do?  Just make sure he catches the ball.
其他的交给我来办
I'll do the rest.
来吧  胆小鬼  好了  来吧
Come on, you wuss! Okay, come on.
快跑  钱德  我来接
Go, Cha... Chandler. I got it!
加油  这边  快点
Come on! This way! Come on!
小心
Look out! - Oof!
哇啊哦
Whoa, whoa.
被女生擒抱  这种画面不多见吧
Tackled by a girl! Bet you don't see that every day.
你这是干嘛
Whoa, whoa, whoa! What's with the tackling?
干嘛
What?
我碰他一下  他就倒下来了
I just touched him and he went over.
好吧  你要来硬的吗  我们也可以来硬的
Okay. You wanna play rough? We can play rough.
准备跳伦巴吧
Let's get ready to rumble!
快点   抓住她
Go, go, go! Get her! Get her!
我喜欢这种运动
I love this game!
你怎么会有那个
Where'd you get that?
我跑的好远
I went really long.
42比21
Forty-two to 21.
跟火鸡一样  罗斯输了
Like the turkey, Ross is done!
你先挑队员  所以你那队的实力比较好
You got to pick first, so you got the better team.
太可悲了  你不肯承认我们赢球
Pathetic! Why can't you just accept that we're winning...
因为我比你厉害
...because I'm better than you?
说得太有道理了  好一声叹息
Pfft!  Oh, what a great argument. Exhaling!
好吧  我要让你心服口服
All right, I'll prove it to you. Okay?
我用乔伊跟你换瑞秋  我还是能赢
I'll trade you Joey for Rachel and I'll still win the game.
什么  男生对女生
What? The guys against the girls?
太可笑了  我只落后三记达阵得分
That's ridiculous because I'm only down by three touchdowns.
那就得分给我看啊
Oh, then bring it on!
除非你害怕会输给几个女生
Unless you're afraid you might lose to a bunch of girls.
好吧  瑞秋  你到摩妮卡那边  乔伊  你跟我一队
Fine. Rachel, you're with Monica. Joey, you're with me.
你竟然把我交换出去
I can not believe you're trading me.
我们也来尝尝看赢球的滋味
Let's see what it's like to be on a winning team for a change.
你会让我摸球吗
You're gonna let me play?
那么好吧
All right, then!
比赛结束了吗  我们要吃饭了吗
The game is over? We eat now?
不  比赛还没有结束  我们在交换队友
No, the game's not over. We're switching teams.
钱德发现我太厉害了  还是跟他同一队比较好
Chandler finds me so intimidating that it's better if we're on the same team.
好吧  开始了
Okay, let's play. Let's go.
等一下
Oh, uh, hold on a second.
荷兰人是从哪里来的
Ahem. Where do Dutch people come from?
那个嘛…
Uh, well, the, uh...
宾州荷兰人来自宾州
...Pennsylvania Dutch come from Pennsylvania.
其他荷兰人呢
And the, uh, other Dutch people?
他们来自荷兰  对吧
They come from somewhere near the Netherlands, right?
少唬人了
Nice try.
荷兰是虚构的地方
The Netherlands is this make-believe place...
彼得潘跟小仙女住在那里
...where Peter Pan and Tinker Bell come from.
天啊
Oh, my.
疯狂地理课结束了  开始打球吧
Enough "geography for the insane." Let's play ball.
不  我不要跟这家伙同队
No. No, I'm not playing with this guy.
我没意见  我受够了
Oh, fine with me. I've had enough of this.
我们就废话少说了  海蒂  你喜欢我的哪个朋友
Let's just cut to the chase. Heidi, which of my boys do you like?
你在做什么   你在做什么
What are you doing? What are you doing? Shh, shh.
我喜欢哪一个
Which do I like?
对  约会  打打闹闹  带他回你的风车
Yeah, for dating, general merriment, taking back to your windmill?
如果一定要现在选…
Well, if I had to choose right now...
对了  我也觉得不可思议…
...which, by the way, I find really weird...
不过我会选钱德
...I would have to say Chandler.
太棒了
Yes!
等一下  她显然没听懂你的问题
Wait a minute. She didn't understand the question.
为什么你不请虎克船长  跟他解释一下
Why don't you have Captain Hook explain it to her?
抱歉  那是我的真心话
I'm sorry. That is my truth.
你听到了吗   那是她的真心话 "我让你追她"先生
You hear that? That is her truth, Mr. "I'll Let You Have Her"!
我赢了  你输了  我是最棒的
I win! You suck! I rule all!
帮我跳迷你波浪舞庆祝一下
Mini-wave in celebration of me!
我想我的答案要改成  "我谁都不要选"
I am now thinking I would like to change my answer to "no one."
什么
What?
我发现你很肤浅
I now find you shallow, and, um...
是个呆瓜
...a dork.
再见
Bye-bye.
干得好
Heh. Nice going.
你害自己几个月没有性生活
You just saved yourself a couple months of sex.
那不重要   因为她选了我
It doesn't matter, because she picked me.
从现在开始   我可以去约会
From now on, I get the dates...
星期六晚上  你只能待在家里看烹饪节目
...and you stay home on Saturday nights watching Ready, Set, Cook!
别说了  时间急迫
Save the breakthroughs for therapy. The clock is ticking.
我们没时间了  我们输给女生
We have no time, and we are losing to girls.
我们不会输给女生
We're not gonna lose to girls.
现在比数是42比21
It's 42-21!
该死  刚刚我还赢那么多
This sucks! I was just up by that much!
我们到底要不要比赛  来吧  你们这些娘娘腔
Are we playing football or what? Come on, you hairy-backed Marys!
我们非赢不可  我们为全世界的女人而战
We have to do this. We're playing for women everywhere.
想像你们的每一次烂约会
Think about every lousy date you ever had.
每次亲热时  男人的眼睛都盯着电视看
Every guy who kept one eye on the TV while you were making out.
天啊  你也跟装了玻璃假眼的男人约会
Oh, my God. You dated someone with a glass eye too?
加油  好吗  这都是为了女人  痛宰他们
Come on, okay? This is for all womankind. Let's kill them!
对  痛宰他们
Yeah! Kill them!
好吧  我也想痛宰他们
All right, I want to kill them too.
但他们是男生
But they're boys.
我们该怎么打败三个男生
You know, how are we gonna beat three boys?
还有一分钟半  我们落后两分
A minute and a half left, and we're down by two points.
两分  姊妹们
Two points, ladies.
菲比  你再做后转身进攻
Phoebe, you do a buttonhook again.
瑞秋   你往前跑
Rachel, you go long.
不   别逼我往前跑  利用我  他们从来不防守我
No, don't make me go long. Use me. They never cover me.
甜心  那是有原因的
Honey, there's a reason.
我一点都不逊  好吗  我可以发挥作用
I'm not lame, okay? I can do something.
你能让我丢球吗   这也是我的比赛
Would you let me throw? This is my game too.
让她丢球吧
Let her throw the ball.
你跑到后面  我会把球传给你  你把球丢给菲比
Sweep behind, I'll pitch it. You throw it downfield to Phoebe.
谢谢你
Thank you.
分开  分开
Break! Break!
好了  开始吧
ROSS: All right, here we go.
32 , 71  开始
Thirty-two, 71, hike!
一  二  三
One Mississippi, two Mississippi, three Mississippi!
快点跑
Go, go, go!
接住
Catch it! Ow!
我真的好抱歉  你没事吧  不  我有事
I'm so sorry. Are you okay? No, I'm not okay!
他们来追我   我不知道该怎么办
They were coming at me, and I didn't know what to do.
只剩三十秒
Thirty seconds left on the timer. Woo-hoo.
我们得把那个笨娃娃带回家
So we get to take that, uh, stupid troll thing home.
来吧  快点  没时间了
Come on! Hurry! We're running out of time.
临战会议   好吧
Huddle up! Okay.
这是我们最后一次临战会议
Oh! This is our last huddle!
好吧  菲比  准备接球  瑞秋
All right, Phoebe, get open. Rachel...
往前跑  好的
...go long. Okay.
分开
Break!
我办到了  达阵得分  我们办到了
Ahh! I did it! Touchdown! We did it!
你们知道吗   这真的很好笑   终点在灯柱那边
You know? Funny thing, actually. The end zone starts at that pole.
你少了五码  所以…
So you're five feet short. So...
我们赢了
...ha-ha-ha, we win! - Whoo!
太棒了
Yes, yes, yes!
等一下  请解释一下
Wait, explain something, though.
如果没有人扑倒瑞秋  比赛还在进行中吧
If nobody tagged Rachel, then isn't the play still going?
让我来   不行  放手
Let me in! Let me in! No way! Let go!
放手  我只是个小女孩
Let go? I'm a tiny little woman!
两位  好了  今天是感恩节
Guys, come on, it's Thanksgiving!
输赢不重要
It's not important who wins or loses.
重点是那个荷兰女孩选了我
The important thing is the Dutch girl picked me!
她选了我  不是你  荷兰爱钱德  谢谢阿姆斯特丹  晚安
Me, not you! Holland loves Chandler! Thank you, Amsterdam! Good night!
哇
Ow!
我们应该多抽空玩足球
We should play football more often.
或许我们可以加入联盟
Maybe there's a league we could join.
不是有国家美式足球联盟吗
Isn't there a "national football league"?
没错  他们会在星期天跟星期一晚上比赛
Yes, there is. They play on Sundays and Monday nights.
该死  星期一晚上我得上班
Oh, shoot! I work Monday nights.
馅料好好吃  你们觉得  我们该包一点给他们吃吗
This stuffing is amazing. Do you think we should bring them some?
他们饿了就会回家
When they're hungry, they'll come in.
放手  不  你才要放手
Let go! No, you let go!
为什么每次都是只剩 我们两个人抱着球不放
How come it's always us left holding the ball?
我不知道  我想其他人就是不在乎
I don't know. I guess the other people just don't care enough.
下雪了
Hey, it's starting to snow.
球给我   放手  快点
Give it to me! Let go! Let it go! Come on, let go!